<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes | Academic</title>
    <link>http://blackwell.math.yorku.ca/gmonette/home/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://blackwell.math.yorku.ca/gmonette/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Homes</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>http://blackwell.math.yorku.ca/gmonette/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Homes</title>
      <link>http://blackwell.math.yorku.ca/gmonette/home/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Quotes</title>
      <link>http://blackwell.math.yorku.ca/gmonette/home/quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://blackwell.math.yorku.ca/gmonette/home/quotes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The things we consider important are often undervalued by other
disciplines &amp;hellip; One of the most important concepts in Statistics is that of missing data.
For most people it&amp;rsquo;s easy to ignore because much of it is not
very visible.&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Cyntha Struthers and Don McLeish&lt;/em&gt; in a workshop in 2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; in all the sciences, we&amp;rsquo;ve got to make sure that we are supporting the
idea that they&amp;rsquo;re not subject to politics, that they&amp;rsquo;re not skewed by an
agenda, that, as I said before, we make sure that we go where the evidence
leads us.&amp;quot; &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Barack Obama&lt;/em&gt;
We can&amp;rsquo;t just learn what we want to know, but what we should know.
&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Joseph R. Biden&lt;/em&gt;
Often decisions about interventions must be made, even if based on limited
empirical evidence, and we should help decision-makers make sensible
decisions under clearly stated assumptions so that &amp;ldquo;consumers&amp;rdquo; of the
conclusion about the effects of some intervention can honestly weigh the
support for that conclusion. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Donald Rubin&lt;/em&gt;
To teach how to live without certainty, and yet without being paralysed by
hesitation, is perhaps the chief thing that philosophy, in our age, can still
do for those who study it.  &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Bertrand Russell&lt;/em&gt;
Human History becomes more and more a race between education and catastrophe.
&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;H. G. Wells&lt;/em&gt;
Would you rather know the chance of making an assertion of efficacy when the
treatment has no effect, or the chance that the treatment is effective?
&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Frank H. Harrell&lt;/em&gt;
Philosophical unification of the Bayesian and frequentist positions is not likely, nor desirable, since
each illuminates a different aspect of statistical inference. We can hope, however, that we will eventually
have a general methodological unification, with both
Bayesians and frequentists agreeing on a body of standard statistical procedures for general use.
&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;M. J. (Susie) Bayarri and James O. Berger&lt;/em&gt; (2004) &amp;ldquo;The Interplay of Bayesian and Frequentist Analysis.&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;Statistical Science&lt;/em&gt; v. 19. (thanks to Hugh McCague)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rubber hits the road where the data hits the code. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Janet McDougall&lt;/em&gt;
The best thing about being a statistician is that you get to play in
everyone&amp;rsquo;s backyard. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;John W. Tukey,&lt;/em&gt; who, incidentally, coined the terms
&amp;lsquo;software&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;bit&amp;rsquo;.
Once you know hierarchies exist, you see them everywhere &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Ita Kreft and Jan
de Leeuw (1998) &amp;ldquo;Introducing Multilevel Modeling&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;
Once you tune into ellipses, you will begin to see them everywhere &amp;hellip; &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash;
&lt;em&gt;James McMullan&lt;/em&gt;
&amp;ldquo;. . . because of the exiguity of our thought which is able to realize only what it can represent to itself and leaves everything else in an obscurity . . .&amp;rdquo; &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash;
&lt;em&gt;Marcel Proust&lt;/em&gt;, Remembrance of Thing Past: The Prisoner
&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;../pix/duchampwheel.png&#39; alt=&#34;Bicycle Wheel&#34;&gt;
Ellipse and conjugate axis generator &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Marcel Duchamp&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that the artist doesn&amp;rsquo;t know what he does. I attach even more
importance to the spectator than to the artist. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Marcel Duchamp&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hate a liar more than I hate a thief. A thief is after my salary &amp;ndash; a
liar is after my reality. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;50 Cent&lt;/em&gt;
No amount of experimentation will prove me right; a single experiment
can prove me wrong. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Albert Einstein&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best thing about being a statistician is that you get a license to poke
your nose into everyone else&amp;rsquo;s business. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; (??)
The best thing about universities is individual freedom, the worst thing is
collective irresponsibility. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;David Northrup&lt;/em&gt;
Humanists believe that the world has a fixed number of mysteries, so that
when one is solved, our sense of wonder is diminished. Scientists believe
that the world has endless mysteries, so that when one is solved, there are
always new ones to ponder. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;D. O. Hebb quoted by Steven Pinker&lt;/em&gt;
Far better an approximate answer to the right question, which is often vague,
than an exact answer to the wrong question, which can always be made precise.
&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;John W. Tukey,&lt;/em&gt; (1962), &amp;ldquo;The future of data analysis.&amp;rdquo; Annals of
Mathematical Statistics 33, 1-67.
A bad answer to a good question may be far better than a good answer to a bad
question. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; a graduate class extrapolating from Tukey&amp;rsquo;s dictum.
It is better to know some of the questions than all of the answers.
&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;James Thurber&lt;/em&gt;
I have a lot of questions . . . but I don&amp;rsquo;t know what they are. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; overheard
at the end of what must have been an inspiring lecture
The worst, i.e., most dangerous, feature of  &amp;lsquo;accepting the null hypothesis&amp;rsquo;
is the giving up of explicit uncertainty . . . Mathematics can sometimes be
put in such black-and-white terms, but our knowledge or belief about the
external world never can. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;John W. Tukey.&lt;/em&gt; (1991). &amp;ldquo;The Philosophy of
Multiple Comparisons.&amp;rdquo; Statistical Science 6, 100&amp;ndash;116.
Where there is no uncertainty there cannot be truth. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Richard Feynman&lt;/em&gt;
(confirmed by Bill Langford)
So far as the theories of mathematics are about reality, they are not
certain; so far as they are certain, they are not about reality.
&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Albert Einstein&lt;/em&gt;
Doubt is not a pleasant condition, but certainty is absurd. - &lt;em&gt;Voltaire&lt;/em&gt;
Art is a lie that enables us to realize the truth. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Pablo Picasso&lt;/em&gt;
At their best, graphics are instruments for reasoning. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Edward Tufte&lt;/em&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.edwardtufte.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;www.edwardtufte.com&lt;/a&gt;
An elementary demonstration is one that requires no knowledge &amp;mdash; just an
infinite amount of intelligence. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Richard Feynman.&lt;/em&gt;
All models are wrong but some are useful.
&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;George E.P. Box&lt;/em&gt;
All models are wrong but, we hope, not as wrong as the ones we used earlier.
&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; paraphrased from &lt;em&gt;Isaac Asimov&lt;/em&gt;
&amp;lsquo;All models are wrong&amp;rsquo; is a model, thus must be wrong. Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s useful
&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; paraphrased from a comment on a blog.
&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;img width=&#39;300&#39; height=&#39;500&#39; src=&#39;../pix/boxcox.gif&#39; alt=&#34;Box and Cox&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I heard what you were saying! You know nothing of my work! You mean my whole
fallacy is wrong. How you got to teach a course in anything is totally
amazing! &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Marshall McLuhan as himself in Annie Hall&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The business of the statistician is to catalyze the scientific learning
process. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;George E. P. Box&lt;/em&gt;
There are no routine statistical question; only questionable statistical
routines. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;D.R. Cox&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We at York must give special emphasis to the humanizing of man, freeing him
from those pressures which mechanize the mind, which make for routine
thinking, which divorce thinking and feeling, which permit custom to dominate
intelligence, which freeze awareness of the human spirit and its
possibilities&amp;hellip; &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Murray G. Ross&lt;/em&gt;
It is better to be wrong than to be vague. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Freeman Dyson&lt;/em&gt;
It is much more important to be clear than to be correct. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Blair Wheaton&lt;/em&gt;
Science may be described as the art of systematic over-simplification. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash;
&lt;em&gt;Karl Popper&lt;/em&gt;
There are three kinds of lies: lies, damned lies, and statistics. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Mark
Twain&lt;/em&gt; with attribution to &lt;em&gt;Benjamin Disraeli&lt;/em&gt;
Lies &amp;mdash; damned lies &amp;mdash; and statistics &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Leonard Henry Courtney&lt;/em&gt; with attribution
to a &amp;ldquo;Wise Statesman,&amp;rdquo; possibly Disraeli [see
http://www.york.ac.uk/depts/maths/histstat/lies.htm]
Statistical thinking will one day be as necessary for efficient citizenship
as the ability to read and write. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;S. Wilks&lt;/em&gt; attributing to &lt;em&gt;H. G. Wells&lt;/em&gt;
A certain elementary training in statistical method is becoming as necessary
for anyone living in this world of today as reading and writing. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash;  &lt;em&gt;H. G. Wells&lt;/em&gt;
in &amp;ldquo;The Informative Content of Education,&amp;rdquo; The Presidential Address to
the Educational Science Section of the British Association for the
Advancement of Science, given on September 2nd, 1937.
Statistical literacy is a necessary precondition for an educated citizenship
in a technological democracy &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Gerd Gigenrenzer et al.&lt;/em&gt;
It is easy to lie with statistics. It is hard to tell the truth without it. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash;
&lt;em&gt;Andrejs Dunkels&lt;/em&gt;
Data analysis is an aid to thinking and not a replacement for. &lt;br&gt;
&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Richard Shillington&lt;/em&gt;
Methodology should never be allowed to displace intelligence. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; paraphrased
from &lt;em&gt;Leland Wilkinson,&lt;/em&gt; I think
Another thing about fit indices is that they are used all too often as
substitutes for thinking. In most cases, statistical analysis should be not
about determining the &amp;ldquo;best fitting&amp;rdquo; model according to a single numerical
criterion. In any given research there hopefully are underlying substantive
theory and knowledge, the research hopefully is guided by research questions
and knowledge about control variables, there is a distinction between primary
and secondary interest, a single research often has elements of hypothesis
testing as well as exploration, etc. etc. Fit indices in the ?IC family are
useful only as a secondary type of summary information, but research
questions and existing  knowledge are more important.  &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Tom Snijders&lt;/em&gt;
If you try to estimate everything, you will end up estimating nothing. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; [I
forget who said this but I&amp;rsquo;d like to know!]
Fishing for hypotheses is like throwing a dart at a wall and then drawing a
target around it. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash;  &lt;em&gt;Andrée Monette&lt;/em&gt;
When statistics are not based on strictly accurate calculations, they mislead
instead of guide. The mind easily lets itself be taken in by the false
appearance of exactitude which statistics retain in their mistakes, and
confidently adopts errors clothed in the form of mathematical truth.
&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Alexis de Tocqueville&lt;/em&gt; [With the benefit of a few centuries to reflect on this, we
appreciate that the accuracy of the calculations is only one of many
requirements to ensure that statistics guide and not mislead]
Causal interpretation of the results of regression analysis of observational
data is a risky business.  The responsibility rests entirely on the shoulders
of the researcher, because the shoulders of the statistical technique cannot
carry such strong inferences. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Jan de Leeuw.&lt;/em&gt;
Correlation is not causation - but it sure helps &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Edward Tufte&lt;/em&gt;
Correlation does not imply causation but it does waggle its eyebrows
suggestively and gesture furtively while mouthing &amp;rsquo;look over there.&amp;rsquo; &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Randall
Munroe, xkcd.com.&lt;/em&gt;
OK! Correlation does not imply causation yada yada. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Paul Krugman&lt;/em&gt;
Do I love you because you&amp;rsquo;re beautiful, or are you beautiful because I love
you?  &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Prince Topher&lt;/em&gt; to Cinderella, philosophizing on causality
&amp;hellip; a primary objective in the design and analysis of observational studies
is to control, through sampling and statistical adjustment, the possible
biasing effects of those confounding variables that can be measured: a
primary objective of in the evaluation of observational studies is to
speculate about the remaining biasing effects of those confounding variables
that cannot be [or: were not] measured. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Donald B Rubin (Matched Sampling
for Causal Effects, 2006)&lt;/em&gt;
Not everything that can be counted counts, and not everything that counts can
be counted. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Albert Einstein&lt;/em&gt;
If a man is offered a fact which goes against his instincts, he will
scrutinize it closely, and unless the evidence is overwhelming, he will
refuse to believe it. If, on the other hand, he is offered something which
affords a reason for acting in accordance to his instincts, he will accept it
even on the slightest evidence.  &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Bertrand Russell&lt;/em&gt;
There&amp;rsquo;s no crime in being ignorant. Problems arise when people who don&amp;rsquo;t know
they&amp;rsquo;re ignorant rise to power. &lt;br&gt;
&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Neil deGrasse Tyson (with thanks to Jen Agg)&lt;/em&gt;
It ain&amp;rsquo;t what they don&amp;rsquo;t know that&amp;rsquo;s the problem &amp;mdash; it&amp;rsquo;s what they know that
ain&amp;rsquo;t so &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; said of members of the U.S. Congress by ?? (communicated by David
Brillinger).  Variants aimed at different groups are attributed to sources
ranging from Will Rogers to Ronald Reagan.
Moral indignation is jealousy wearing a halo. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;H. G. Wells&lt;/em&gt;
If you can&amp;rsquo;t be a good example, be a horrible warning. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; scrawled in a
country bathroom.
From the Globe &amp;amp; Mail, Social Studies column by Michael Kesterton, September
9, 2003:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Random: Washington-area teenagers have been overheard saying such things as:
&amp;ldquo;Did you see that outfit she was wearing? That was so random!&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Who invited
those random kids to this party?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;I never watch the news on TV. It&amp;rsquo;s too,
like, random.&amp;rdquo; The adjective seems to mean &amp;ldquo;serendipitous,&amp;rdquo; but is more
value-neutral. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s actually rather specific the way students use it,&amp;rdquo;
English teacher Patrick Welsh tells The Washington Post, adding &amp;ldquo;the
brightest of the bright kids are the ones who tend to use it.&amp;rdquo;
I have a soft spot for secret passageways, bookshelves that open into
silence, staircases that go down into a void, and hidden safes. I even have
one myself, but I won&amp;rsquo;t tell you where. At the other end of the spectrum are
statistics which I hate with all my heart. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Luis Buñuel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What difference does it make to the dead, the orphans and the homeless,
whether the mad destruction is wrought under the name of totalitarianism or
the holy name of liberty or democracy? &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Mahatma Gandhi&lt;/em&gt; (1869 - 1948),
Non-Violence in Peace and War
No problem is so big or so complicated that it can&amp;rsquo;t be run away from. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash;
&lt;em&gt;Linus van Pelt (Peanuts)&lt;/em&gt;
Natural Selection is a mechanism for generating an exceedingly high degree of
improbability. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;R. A. Fisher&lt;/em&gt;
In times of change learners inherit the earth, while the learned find
themselves beautifully equipped to deal with a world that no longer exists. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash;
&lt;em&gt;Eric Hoffer&lt;/em&gt;
Being a statistician means never having to say you&amp;rsquo;re certain &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; ??
There&amp;rsquo;ll be a time when not having strong opinions about anything will be
seen not as a character flaw, but as a virtue. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Alberto Cairo&lt;/em&gt;
It has often and confidently been asserted, that man&amp;rsquo;s origin can never be
known: but ignorance more frequently begets confidence than does knowledge:
it is those who know little, and not those who know much, who so positively
assert that this or that problem will never be solved by science.
&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Charles Darwin&lt;/em&gt;
One of the painful things about our time is that those who feel certainty are
stupid, and those with any imagination and understanding are filled with
doubt and indecision. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Bertrand Russell&lt;/em&gt;
The methods of statistics turn art into science &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; paraphrased from
&lt;em&gt;Arnold Zellner&lt;/em&gt;
Statistics is an art struggling to be a science. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash;  &lt;em&gt;Heather Krause&lt;/em&gt;
A data scientist is a statistician who lives in San Francisco &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; ?
A data scientist is a statistician who is useful &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Hadley Wickham&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A popular joke is that  &amp;ldquo;a data scientist is a statistician who lives in San
Francisco,&amp;rdquo; but Hadley Wickham, a Ph. D. statistician, floated a more cynical
take on Twitter: &amp;ldquo;a data scientist is a statistician who is useful.&amp;rdquo;
Statisticians are the guardians of statistical inference, and it is our
responsibility to educate practitioners about using models appropriately, and
the hazards of ignoring model assumptions when making inferences. But many
model assumptions are only truly met under idealized conditions, and thus, as
Box eloquently argued, one must think carefully about when statistical
inferences are valid. When they are not, statisticians are caught in the
awkward position, as Wickham suggests, of always saying &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo;. This position
can be dissatisfying.  &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Ben Baumer&lt;/em&gt; in &amp;ldquo;A Data Science Course for
Undergraduates: Thinking with Data&amp;rdquo;, March, 2015
The absence of evidence is not evidence of absence &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Carl Sagan&lt;/em&gt; and many many
others cautioning against concluding that the null hypothesis is correct when
you merely fail to reject it.
The absence of evidence is not evidence of absence &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Donald Rumsfeld&lt;/em&gt; to
George W. Bush concluding the alternative hypothesis to justify the attack on Iraq.
A difference of evidence is not in itself evidence of a difference &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; ??&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The difference between &amp;lsquo;significant&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;not significant&amp;rsquo; is not itself
statistically significant. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Andrew Gelman and Hal Stern, American Statistician&lt;/em&gt; (2006)
If it were a fact, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be called intelligence &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Donald Rumsfeld&lt;/em&gt; interviewed by Stephen Colbert&lt;br&gt;
Wow! &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Stephen Colbert&lt;/em&gt;
Changing your mind is the only sure proof you can offer that you&amp;rsquo;ve got one
&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Richard P. Feynman&lt;/em&gt; quoting ??
Ignorance more frequently begets confidence than does knowledge.
&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Charles Darwin, The Descent of Man&lt;/em&gt;
Statisticians learn not to be surprised by the improbable &amp;mdash; which is usually
probable &amp;mdash; only by the improbably improbable &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; ??
One might perchance say this was probable that things improbable oft will hap
to men &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Aristotle quoting Agathon&lt;/em&gt;
Railing against collinearity is like railing against gravity &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; anonymous
referee commenting on an article on collinearity and variance inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There once was a student of yore&lt;br&gt;
Whose inference truly was poor.&lt;br&gt;
From a sample of one,&lt;br&gt;
His mean was .1,&lt;br&gt;
And the variance he found was .4.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;G. Eric Moorhouse&lt;/em&gt;
If you think you understand X that&amp;rsquo;s a sure sign that you don&amp;rsquo;t understand X
&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; a metaquote.
Believe those who are seeking the truth. Doubt those who find it.
&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;André Gide&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
If you amplify everything, you hear nothing. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Jon Stewart&lt;/em&gt;
Seek the company of those who seek the truth, and run away from those who
have found it.
&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Vaclav Havel&lt;/em&gt;
The scientist is not a person who gives the right answers, he is one who asks
the right questions.
&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Claude Lévi-Strauss&lt;/em&gt; (Le Cru et le Cuit, 1964)
We are inclined to believe those whom we do not know because they have never
deceived us.
&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Samuel Johnson&lt;/em&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Faith&amp;rdquo; is a fine invention&lt;br&gt;
For Gentlemen who &lt;em&gt;see!&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt;
But Microscopes are prudent &lt;br&gt;
In an Emergency! &lt;br&gt;
&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Emily Dickinson&lt;/em&gt;
Let us change our traditional attitude to the construction of programs:
Instead of imagining that our main task is to instruct a computer what to do,
let us concentrate rather on explaining to humans what we want the computer
to do.
&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Donald E. Knuth, 1984&lt;/em&gt;
&amp;hellip;academic administrative positions must be about both leadership and
management because one without the other leads to no results or to trivial
results. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Sheila Embleton&lt;/em&gt; &lt;!-- For a few reflections on academic governance that
are both deep and practical see a Y File article.--&gt;
It&amp;rsquo;s foie. You&amp;rsquo;ve got to get it right  &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; the &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;King of Ginger&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; rejecting a
dish performing quality control at The Black Hoof
There&amp;rsquo;s no task so impressive that it can&amp;rsquo;t be ruined by a rubric &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Hans
Krause&lt;/em&gt;
It&amp;rsquo;s not the data alone, but analytics &amp;mdash; and people trained to use them &amp;mdash;
that generate real value from big data. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Suzanne Gordon, CIO, SAS&lt;/em&gt;
After Eisenhower, you couldn&amp;rsquo;t win an election without radio. After JFK, you
couldn&amp;rsquo;t win an election without television. After Obama, you couldn&amp;rsquo;t win an
election without social networking. I predict that in 2012, you won&amp;rsquo;t be able
to win an election without big data. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Alistair Croll&lt;/em&gt;
The real battlefront is not between Islam and the West. The real battlefront is
between all the faith traditions . . . atheists among that . . . all the
moderates against extremists. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Imam Feisal Abdul Rauf&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;
   &lt;img src=&#39;http://mtor.sci.yorku.ca/MATH6642/pix/rot.gif&#39; alt=&#34;AVP and Suppression&#34;&gt;
Suppression and the AVP   
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a scientific survey. It&amp;rsquo;s a random survey. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Representative
Daniel Webster&lt;/em&gt; voting in May 2012 for the abolition of the American Community
Survey, the U.S. analogue of the Canadian &amp;ldquo;long form.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a young man of Lyon&lt;br&gt;
Who normally fished on the Rhône.&lt;br&gt;
One hour he caught seven.&lt;br&gt;
Next five.&lt;br&gt;
Then eleven.&lt;br&gt;
Not normal!  Those fish were Poisson.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;G. Eric Moorhouse&lt;/em&gt;
90% of the world&amp;rsquo;s data was generated in the last two years and 80% of that
data is unstructured &amp;hellip; &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Geeknet, Inc. 2012&lt;/em&gt;
Statistical rituals largely eliminate statistical thinking in the social
sciences. Rituals are indispensable for identification with social groups,
but they should be the subject rather than the procedure of science.
&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Gerd Gigerenzer&lt;/em&gt;
&amp;hellip; statistics is fraught with contextual issues, which is the nature of the
discipline, whereas often mathematics strips off the context in order to
abstract and generalize. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;J. Michael Shaughnessy&lt;/em&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve worked in so many areas &amp;mdash; I&amp;rsquo;m sort of a dilettante. Basically, I&amp;rsquo;m not
interested in doing research and I never have been. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in
understanding, which is quite a different thing. And often to understand
something you have to work it out yourself because no one else has done it.
&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;David Blackwell&lt;/em&gt;
&amp;hellip; no scientific worker has a fixed level of significance at which from year to year, and
in all circumstances, he rejects hypotheses; he rather gives his mind to each particular
case in the light of his evidence and his ideas.
&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Sir Ronald A. Fisher (1956) quoted in Gerd Gigerenzer (2004) &amp;ldquo;Mindless Statistics&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do intelligent people engage in statistical rituals rather than in statistical thinking?
Every person of average intelligence can understand that &lt;code&gt;\(p(D|H)\)&lt;/code&gt; is not the same as &lt;code&gt;\(p(H|D)\)&lt;/code&gt;.
That this insight fades away when it comes to hypothesis testing suggests that the cause is
not intellectual but social and emotional. Here is a hypothesis:
The conflict between statisticians, both suppressed by and inherent in the textbooks,
has become internalized in the minds of researchers. The statistical ritual is a form of
conflict resolution, like compulsive hand washing, which makes it resistant to arguments.
&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Gerd Gigerenzer (2004) &amp;ldquo;Mindless Statistics&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; causal vocabulary was virtually prohibited [in Statistics] for more than
half a century. And when you prohibit speech, you prohibit thought and stifle principles,
methods, and tools.
&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Judea Pearl (2018) &amp;ldquo;The Book of Why&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In observational studies, it must be remembered that the issue of bias
reduction nearly always dominates the issue of variance reduction:
a precise estimate that is badly biased can be more deceptive than helpful,
and matched
sampling is a key tool for reducing this bias without compromising
the integrity or
objectivity of the study&amp;rsquo;s design.
&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Donald Rubin (2006) &amp;ldquo;Matched Sampling for Causal Effects&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The special training statisticans receive in mapping real problems into
formal probability models, computing inferences from data and models,
and exploring the adequacy of these inferences, is not really part of any
other formal discipline, yet is often critical to the quality of
empirical research.
&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Donald Rubin (1993) &amp;ldquo;The Future of Statistics&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only victories that leave no regret are those that are gained over ignorance.
&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Napoléon Bonaparte&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing worse than fighting with your allies is fighting with no allies.
&lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Winston Churchill&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a foreboding of an America in my children&amp;rsquo;s or grandchildren&amp;rsquo;s time &amp;ndash; when
the United States is a service and information economy; when nearly all the manufacturing industries
have slipped away to other countries;
when awesome technological powers are in the hands of a very few, and no one representing the public interest can
even grasp the issues;
when the people have lost the ability to set their own agendas or knowledgeably question
those in authority;
when, clutching our crystals and
nervously consulting our horoscopes, our critical
faculties in decline, unable to distinguish between what feels good and what&amp;rsquo;s true,
we slide, almost without noticing, back into superstition and darkness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dumbing down
of America is most evident in the slow decay of substantive content in the enormously influential media,
the 30-second
sound bites (now down to 10 seconds or less), lowest common denominator programming,
credulous presentations on pseudoscience and superstition, but especially
a kind of celebration of ignorance. &lt;br&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Carl Sagan&lt;/em&gt; (1995) &lt;em&gt;The Demon-Haunted World: Science as a Candle in the Dark&lt;/em&gt; cited
on MSNBC, The 11th Hour, by Brian Williams, July 12, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
